# **HUSSAIN ALI MURTAZA**

+92-335-9390000 • hussainseikh5823@gmail.com • Age: 24

# **Career Objective**

Looking forward to work with an organization where I can polish my professional skills, enhance my experience, implement my knowledge. I want to give my best for the success of your organization to work for the betterment of my fellow human beings

# **Education**

NFC IE&FR Faisalabad (CGPA 3.65)

Bachelor in Chemical Engineering

2013-2017

**Govt. Post Graduate College D.G.KHAN** (A<sup>+</sup>)

F.Sc. Pre-Engineering

D.G Khan, Pakistan 2010-2012

D.G School and College (A)

Matriculation

D.G Khan, Pakistan
2008-2010

# **Experience**

#### **DG** khan Cement Company

Second Most efficient and self-energized Cement plant of world

Internee Engineer: June 2015 – July 2015

D.G Khan, Pakistan

- Technical Skills: Understanding of clinker forming process from limestone and clay
- *Teamwork:* Coordinated with 10 group members from different universities for complete plant layout and final report of 30 days

# **Academic Activities**

Final Year Project Faisalabad, Pakistan

Simultaneous Removal of Acid Gasses and Mercaptan from Natural Gas *Vision: June 2016 – July 2017* 

- Determined: Removal of acid gasses and mercaptan from natural gas to increase productivity using chemical absorption in economical way with maximum conversion of natural gas from mercaptan by using 5 parallel reactions
- Teamwork: Work with 4 group members and submitted 150 pages thesis report

# **Additional**

- Interpersonal Skills: Motivated and persistent, Self-starter, Improvise
- Soft Skills: Aspen Plus and HYSYS, Microsoft office, Visio and Matlab
- Interests: Computer Applications, Reading new developments in Chemical Engineering